<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerri Shotts</title>
    <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kerri Shotts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2015 Kerri Shotts. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 22:59:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kerrishotts.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>30% Off Preorder of my new book!</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2016/02/14-Pre-order-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 22:59:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2016/02/14-Pre-order-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Packt Publishing was kind enough to send me a code that you can use to get a 30% discount when you pre-order my new book, &lt;em&gt;Mastering
PhoneGap Mobile Application Development&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When pre-ordering the book at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/1K7Bjfn&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/1K7Bjfn&lt;/a&gt;, use the following code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;NORA50y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s final stages are complete, and so the final release date should be sometime this month (February 2016). So, you might not want to wait too long!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the iPad Pro</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2016/01/12-iPad-Pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 16:37:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2016/01/12-iPad-Pro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I purchased an iPad Pro just before the end of 2015. As a mobile app developer, I needed to ensure
that my apps would work on the larger screen, and although one can test this to some degree in the
simulators, there really is no substitute for having a physical device in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind, then, that I&amp;rsquo;ve only had the device for a couple weeks, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give some
thoughts on what I think of the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-impressions:36bbfacf45c44a64d8070c8ca8014ac0&#34;&gt;Initial impressions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some my initial impressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Damn&lt;/em&gt;, this thing is big!&amp;rdquo; was probably my first thought upon seeing the device in person. And
it is &amp;ndash; 12.9&amp;rdquo; diagonal tells the tale, but it&amp;rsquo;s that much more imposing upon physically seeing
it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not that heavy, though!&amp;rdquo; came a few thoughts later, &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d purchased the device and
pulled it out of the box. One doesn&amp;rsquo;t get a perfect feel for the weight, since the devices have
anti-theft cables while in store.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Does app xyz work?&amp;rdquo; was one of my next thoughts. Namely, do &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; apps work? Of course, not all of
them have been updated to use the larger screen (which is why I bought it), but I wanted to make
sure that my apps didn&amp;rsquo;t crash or do something really crazy. Thankfully they didn&amp;rsquo;t do either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Finally, a keyboard I can type on!&amp;rdquo; The iPad Pro (in apps that support the full display
resolution) supplies a much better on-screen keyboard. It has a number row, along with quick
access to the symbols above those numbers. Having a full set of punctuation and brackets available
is also nice. When in landscape, the keys are big enough I can type quite quickly with decent
accuracy, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Damn, this thing is big!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; this is still my thought every time I pick it up. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;ll
ever go away. On the other hand, it makes me feel like everything else is small by comparison,
too, especially my iPad Mini 4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-i-don-t-like:36bbfacf45c44a64d8070c8ca8014ac0&#34;&gt;Things I don&amp;rsquo;t like&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No device is perfect, and the iPad Pro certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the things I don&amp;rsquo;t like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The home screen is entirely too sparse. With the increased resolution, Apple could easily have
increased the number rows and columns available on screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Battery life is okay, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t last quite as long as I&amp;rsquo;d like. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m still getting
to know it, so this is a bit skewed at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;iPhone-only apps look downright silly on this screen. Granted, they look silly at 2x on an iPad
Air 2, but the iPad Pro doesn&amp;rsquo;t give an additional scaling factor &amp;ndash; instead it just adds more to
the black border around the app. I don&amp;rsquo;t have many apps that are like this, thankfully!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Apple Pencil</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2016/01/12-Apple-Pencil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 15:12:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2016/01/12-Apple-Pencil/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago I purchased an iPad Pro so that I could use it for development, and also verify
that my existing applications worked correctly. Because it is a larger device, it is important to
also verify that my apps can appropriately scale to the new screen size. This isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;difficult&lt;/em&gt;, and
you can test this in a simulator, but my mantra has and always will be: &amp;ldquo;there is no substitute for
testing on a real device&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this post isn&amp;rsquo;t about what I think about app development, necessarily (although it may generate
some ideas), so enough of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the purchase, I ordered an Apple Pencil. These apparently are in short supply, but I found
a Reddit post that led me to Walmart, and I was able to one online. It arrived a few days later. As
such, I&amp;rsquo;ve only had it for about a week, but I can already say this: the combination of the iPad Pro
and the Apple Pencil is absolutely brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what do I think of this (expensive) combination? Let&amp;rsquo;s get my cons out of the way first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-i-don-t-like:68efd82088bb44c96bfc68b11a42be18&#34;&gt;Things I don&amp;rsquo;t like&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These will be in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m going to lose the thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Apple&amp;rsquo;s infinite wisdom, the Apple Pencil itself isn&amp;rsquo;t magnetized in any way. You&amp;rsquo;d think that
the magnets already present in the iPad Pro (and related covers) would be a fantastic place to
hold the Pencil while it is not in use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nor is there any dedicated place to hold an Apple Pencil, on the iPad Pro or with a cover. There
are some third party solutions cropping up though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The finish is very glossy and slick. If you like more grip, the Pencil may disappoint you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have no problems with how the device charges. There&amp;rsquo;s a lightning connector at the top that you
can plug into your iPad Pro for quick charges, and there&amp;rsquo;s an adapter that you can attach so that
you can use existing lightning cables. Both ways work, though I&amp;rsquo;m using the latter option the
most. In order to charge, though, one detaches the top of the Pencil &amp;ndash; and there&amp;rsquo;s no way to
ensure that it stays connected to the Pencil at all. Losing it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the worst thing in the
world (#FirstWorldProblems, anywone?), but it seems to me like it should have some sort of tether
so that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easily lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can only imagine that at some point in the distant future that Apple would use inductive
charging for the Pencil, so that this point would become moot. But for now, it stands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s long and reasonably thick. It&amp;rsquo;s a little heavy for long periods of use, although not so much
that I&amp;rsquo;m not using it. I could actually stand to have a thicker grip (but I like thick pens), but
I could easily imagine others who might like something a little thinner and shorter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m skating on ice. Although not specific to the Apple Pencil, it&amp;rsquo;s something you will
have to get used to when drawing. I never realized how much I depended upon the natural friction
of pen and paper when stopping strokes &amp;ndash; and so I was overshooting a little bit!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-i-love:68efd82088bb44c96bfc68b11a42be18&#34;&gt;Things I love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My handwriting is translated very nicely to the device, warts and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years back at a conference, I was using an old HP tablet with a stylus, and the
handwriting was a pain in the rear. Latency was awful, as was the actual ability to read the
handwriting later. (Handwriting recognition wasn&amp;rsquo;t so hot either.) Of course, part of this was due
to my lousy handwriting, but it was never a great experience. I found myself wishing I could go
back in time and give myself &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; setup. I can actually enjoy writing on this tablet!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Very few apps support handwriting recognition, but there&amp;rsquo;s a keyboard that does a pretty decent
job at reading my horrific script called &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/yl_G3.i&#34;&gt;MyScript Stylus - Handwriting
Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Latency is very low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having any latency at all during drawing or writing completely destroys the experience for me.
I guess I&amp;rsquo;m just a bit funny that way, but it&amp;rsquo;s one reason why I&amp;rsquo;ve never much liked using
a stylus before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The amount of latency is very dependent upon the app you&amp;rsquo;re using, and the selected tool you are
drawing with. Any tool that draws thin lines should respond very quickly. On the other hand,
a tool with a large, complex brush may still result in latency as the app calculates what should
be rendered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pressure sensitivity is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was another reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t like most dumb stylii.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no real way to configure this, however, unless an app supports it.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/ATHvz.i&#34;&gt;Procreate&lt;/a&gt; is a great app that does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palm rejection is (mostly) great, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was yet another reason I could never get on board with a dumb stylus &amp;ndash; the palm rejection
in most apps just never worked that well for me. Maybe my hands are funny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few times when an app misreads my palm, but not many.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All I know is that drawing and writing is now &lt;strong&gt;SO&lt;/strong&gt; much easier when one can rest their palm on
the device!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Precision is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike some stylii where the nib is this thick rubber black thing and you have no idea which
pixels you&amp;rsquo;ll actually affect, the Pencil gives you a pretty good idea of what you&amp;rsquo;ll edit.
Namely: the pixels under the point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect &amp;ndash; various device orientations seem to yield slightly different results for me.
But it&amp;rsquo;s always within a couple of pixels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can actually fill tight areas with a brush with precision (assuming I know how the brush
itself reacts).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact that the screen is laminated to the glass helps here too, since there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of
space between the Pencil&amp;rsquo;s point and the display. The distance here is not &lt;em&gt;zero&lt;/em&gt;, however, so you
can notice it a little, but it&amp;rsquo;s not nearly enough to throw me, and generally it disappears
quickly as you use the device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Battery life is quite good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think anything ever lasts quite as long as the manufacturer claims, but still, on a full
charge, the Apple Pencil should last a day&amp;rsquo;s worth of work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charging itself is also pretty quick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The battery indicator is in the notification center in case you&amp;rsquo;re ever curious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;app-support:68efd82088bb44c96bfc68b11a42be18&#34;&gt;App support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically the Pencil will work in every app &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;ll just act as a more precise finger. Of course,
to gain pressure sensitivity and tilt support, the app needs to be properly coded to recognize the
Pencil. Some apps are better at this than others, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve used these apps consistently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/ATHvz.i&#34;&gt;Procreate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some really nice brushes, although some do introduce additional latency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supports layers &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; blend modes. This is nice when you&amp;rsquo;re into adult coloring &amp;ndash; you can find
a black-and-white line drawing, paste it into a layer and set the blend mode to &amp;ldquo;Linear Burn&amp;rdquo;, and
then color to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content on an additional layer below the imported image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/b8DAH.i&#34;&gt;Concepts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although portions of the UI are a little clunky (to me), this app offers an infinite canvas, which is
super handy when doodling app ideas, drawing quick mock up sketches, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can draw precise shapes, which is very handy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is one of the few apps that let me snap such shapes to a grid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest features (I think) is the ability to select anything you&amp;rsquo;ve drawn and easily
move it somewhere else (including snapping to the grid). Everything is selectable &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; editable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adobe &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/m52aY.i&#34;&gt;Photoshop Sketch&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/UvYt2.i&#34;&gt;Illustrator Draw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brushes are quite nice, and I like the fact that one can have several variations of the same
brush available within a single tap (say, colors or stroke widths).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Layer support isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as expansive as Procreate, but there is easy support for tracing
images, which is handy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love being able to draw precise shapes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just wish I could go back and edit my prior strokes (or move them around if need be)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts:68efd82088bb44c96bfc68b11a42be18&#34;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;m completely flummoxed by is the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s next to impossible to get any of the
above apps to open an SVG or Adobe Illustrator file directly. I understand some conversion might be
necessary, but the apps don&amp;rsquo;t even make the attempt. And I can even let the non-Adobe apps slide,
but Adobe? C&amp;rsquo;mon! Support SVG/AI as an import source!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no true replacement for Adobe Photoshop or Adobe Illustrator, either &amp;ndash; although Procreate
comes close for Photoshop, and Concepts is very useful as well. So as great as the Pencil is, this
isn&amp;rsquo;t going to replace your workflows in Adobe&amp;rsquo;s desktop applications (unless you remote to your
machine). You&amp;rsquo;d think Adobe would release some tools that would match the &amp;ldquo;pro&amp;rdquo; moniker the iPad Pro
receives &amp;ndash; maybe that&amp;rsquo;s in the wings. I sure hope so, because I&amp;rsquo;d love to have the power of
PhotoShop / Illustrator on the iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting back to app development, the Pencil itself is going to be interesting to develop for,
I think. Apparently the device &amp;ldquo;predicts&amp;rdquo; your movements, and the screen also increases the sampling
rate. Handling both is a little more work than simply tracking a finger. Furthermore, I&amp;rsquo;ve not seen
anything regarding Apple Pencil support in hybrid applications yet. I&amp;rsquo;ve not got any firm ideas in
mind yet, but&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s only been a week, and my brain isn&amp;rsquo;t quite over the holidays yet, either!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling large SQL Query results</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/quicktip/2015/12/15-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 17:53:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/quicktip/2015/12/15-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I encountered an odd problem while working on an app for the current book I&amp;rsquo;m writing. The app worked as-is, but I wanted
to improve the startup performance by using a SQLite database rather than using an XHR to load a large JSON file. I added the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/litehelpers/cordova-sqlite-ext&#34;&gt;cordova-sqlite-ext plugin&lt;/a&gt; because it had built-in support for pre-populated
databases. I also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kerrishotts/Mastering-PhoneGap-Code-Package/blob/master/logology-v12/src/www/js/lib/WebSQL.js&#34;&gt;a promise-based wrapper that I like to use&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should mention that both the JSON and resulting SQLite database are large &amp;ndash; the JSON file is 27MiB and the SQLite database is
45MiB. As such, an unlimited result set from a naive query could return a lot of rows &amp;ndash; nearly 150,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The naive code, by the way, looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;db.query({sql&lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;select lemma from lemmas order by lemma&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;})
  .then((r) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.sortedIndex &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; r.rows.map(r) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; r.lemma })
  ...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This looks like it should work, and it did work in Safari, in Chrome, and in the iOS simulator. However, this failed miserably on
a physical device (yet another example of why it is always important to test on physical devices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there was no error. There was nothing interesting on the console. The app just didn&amp;rsquo;t work right. I investigated
further, and it turned out that the above promise wasn&amp;rsquo;t resolving correctly. What blew my mind was that even unrelated promises
failed to resolve once this particular piece of code was executed. It took an &lt;code&gt;alert(1);&lt;/code&gt; to get any promises to work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I took a closer look and stepped through the native code, and it suddenly occurred to me: the plugin has to transfer a lot of
data over the Cordova bridge. Although querying the SQLite database is a lot faster than iterating over a JSON object, the latter
stays entirely within the JavaScript context. The plugin, on the other hand, was having to transfer data between the native and
hybrid contexts. Furthermore, my wrapper converts the rows in the result set into a normal Array. While this makes for easier
processing later (I can use &lt;code&gt;map&lt;/code&gt; and the like), this also takes time and memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried a shorter query that would return one row. &lt;strong&gt;BOOM&lt;/strong&gt;, it worked. It was now obvious that the problem was related to the
amount of data being selected. So I tried some more numbers. I was able to successfully load up to one-hundred thousand records at
once, but the more records I loaded, the more I recognized a problem: the app would become increasingly unresponsive. As far as
I can tell, this is due in part to the data transfer and also due the conversion of the rows into an array by my wrapper, and
obviously the more data one has to transfer and convert, the longer it takes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point after one-hundred thousand records, the process breaks down completely, and the data is never returned to the promise.
As such, the promise is just sitting there, twiddling its thumbs, waiting for data that will never arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can we fix this? Turns out, rather easily. SQLite understands the &lt;code&gt;LIMIT&lt;/code&gt; keyword, which allows us to break up a query into
smaller segments. Typically this might be used for paging a result set, but it works for our purposes as well. This is what the
final result looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;db.query({sql&lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;select count(*) as numLemmas from lemmas&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;}).then((r) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; ITEMS_PER &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000DD; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;10000&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; numLemmas &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; r.rows[&lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000DD; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;].numLemmas;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; p &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Promise.resolve();
    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000DD; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;; i &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; numLemmas; i &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; ITEMS_PER) {
        p &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; p.then(() &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; db.query({sql&lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;select lemma from lemmas order by lemma limit ?, ?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;, binds&lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;[i, ITEMS_PER]}))
             .then((r) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.sortedIndex.push(...r.rows.map((r) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; r.lemma)));
    }
    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; p;
})...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the above code does:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selects the number of records that the query will return&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creates a series of promises that process only a portion of the total query, in 10,000 record blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The key here is &lt;code&gt;LIMIT ?, ?&lt;/code&gt;. The first parameter is the starting position in the result set, and the second is the number of
records that are returned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pushes the results into the target array.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, for a query that returns nearly 150,000 records, this has to generate 15 queries. Interestingly enough, however, the
return is nearly instantaneous, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t ever block the app itself, so everything remains responsive, and should the query ever
return even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; rows, the app will still continue to function correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, of course, an upper limit to how much we can store in an array, of course. That said, JavaScript doesn&amp;rsquo;t do terribly
badly here &amp;ndash; A sorted 150,000 array of words doesn&amp;rsquo;t take up much space at all. Right now the app is consuming around 20MiB of
RAM using Xcode&amp;rsquo;s profiler, and that&amp;rsquo;s with a full DOM and a few views on screen. While this might be tight on devices with
a ridiculously low amount of RAM, it&amp;rsquo;s more than workable on any device within the last three or so years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Kerri</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 23:09:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe height=&#34;577&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;border:none&#34;  src=&#34;http://photokandy.wufoo.com/embed/m7x3k1/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photokandy.wufoo.com/forms/m7x3k1/&#34;&gt;Contact me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cordova/PhoneGap &amp; CSP (QuickTip)</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/quicktip/2015/11/25-cordova-csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 22:29:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/quicktip/2015/11/25-cordova-csp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to share a few tips regarding the Content Security Policy meta tag that we need to use in PhoneGap/Cordova apps. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to cover &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the gory details &amp;mdash; for that, there are plenty of great sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/security/content-security-policy/&#34;&gt;Content Security Policy (HTML5Rocks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/CSP/Using_Content_Security_Policy&#34;&gt;Using Content Security Policy (MDN)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just going to focus on a few specific use cases when it comes to the intersection of CSP and Cordova/PhoneGap, but there’s a couple things we need to mention first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-csp-meta-tag:e5b6aa8725667982def880fbba897e59&#34;&gt;The CSP Meta Tag&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSP directives are specified by a &lt;code&gt;meta&lt;/code&gt; tag, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;http-equiv=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Content-Security-Policy&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;contents=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;...&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;csp-directives:e5b6aa8725667982def880fbba897e59&#34;&gt;CSP Directives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSP controls what sources are permitted and what sources aren&amp;rsquo;t. Because there are many different types of assets our page might need, CSP also allows us to be very granular with respect to what types of assets can be loaded from which sources. There&amp;rsquo;s several directives available, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;directive&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;img-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image sources (like PNG, JPG, SVG, etc.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;media-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Video/audio sources&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;script-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Script sources&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;style-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Stylesheet sources&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;font-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Webfont sources&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fallback for most directives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t the entire list of available directives, so you’ll want to check out the links at the head of this article for all the possibilities, but this should give you a pretty good idea of the granularity of CSP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that there is a hierarchy of sorts — if you don&amp;rsquo;t specify &lt;code&gt;img-src&lt;/code&gt;, but do specify &lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt; is used instead. If you specify both, however, the values won&amp;rsquo;t inherit from &lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;csp-sources:e5b6aa8725667982def880fbba897e59&#34;&gt;CSP Sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source is either a URL or a special keyword. A URL can look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.example.com&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; allow resources from this domain, including any pages on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://*.example.com&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; allow resources from this domain, including any subdomains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;*://*.example.com&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; allow resources from this domain, any subdomains, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; any URL scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;*://*.example.com:*&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; allow resources from this domain, any subdomains, any URL scheme, &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; any port.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: Although it might appear that you can use wildcards anywhere, you can&amp;rsquo;t. You can only use a wildcard for the URL scheme, the left part of the domain, and the port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four keywords that you can also use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;none&#39;&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; indicates that no source is permitted. This disables access for the specified directive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;self&#39;&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; indicates that local resources are permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;unsafe-inline&#39;&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; permits inline scripts/styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;unsave-eval&#39;&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; permits &lt;code&gt;eval()&lt;/code&gt; and its ilk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;csp-syntax:e5b6aa8725667982def880fbba897e59&#34;&gt;CSP Syntax&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each directive can have any number of sources. Each one is separated by a space. The entire set of directives are separated by semicolons. This makes things a little difficult to read, but that&amp;rsquo;s the way it&amp;rsquo;s built. For example, here&amp;rsquo;s a sample CSP tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;http-equiv=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Content-Security-Policy&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; 
 &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;default-src &amp;#39;self&amp;#39; https://*.example.com;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;              img-src &amp;#39;self&amp;#39; https://images.example.com data:;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;           script-src &amp;#39;self&amp;#39; https://scripts.example.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a terribly useful CSP, but it does illustrate the syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;common-cordova-uses:e5b6aa8725667982def880fbba897e59&#34;&gt;Common Cordova Uses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that out of the way, here&amp;rsquo;s some common tasks you might need to perform  in a Cordova app — along with the directives you need to specify to permit them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;task&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;directive&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;iOS Support&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gap://*&lt;/code&gt; (1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Allow web socket communication&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ws://*&lt;/code&gt; (2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Execute / load local resources&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;self&#39;&lt;/code&gt; (3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Load &lt;code&gt;data:&lt;/code&gt; images&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;img-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;data:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Permit &lt;code&gt;eval()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;script-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;unsafe-eval&#39;&lt;/code&gt;   (4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Permit inline scripting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;script-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;unsafe-inline&#39;&lt;/code&gt; (5)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Permit inline styles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;style-src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;unsafe-inline&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is critically important for your Cordova/PhoneGap apps running on iOS. Without it, plugins and Cordova events won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you use web sockets for communication, you’ll need to allow this URL scheme. Our example allows communication with any host on any port, but ideally you&amp;rsquo;ll be more specific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should always have &lt;code&gt;&#39;self&#39;&lt;/code&gt; in any directive so that you can load local resources. If you override any other directive, you’ll need to specify &lt;code&gt;&#39;self&#39;&lt;/code&gt; there too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only allow &lt;code&gt;eval()&lt;/code&gt; if you absolutely must do so. Some plugins, libraries and frameworks will require it, but if you can avoid it, this should be avoided, as it can be a huge security hole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only allow inline scripting if you absolutely must. Again, some frameworks and such might require it, but it&amp;rsquo;s a huge security risk if you’re injecting dynamic HTML using untrusted data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-browsersync:e5b6aa8725667982def880fbba897e59&#34;&gt;What about BrowserSync?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really, really, really like to use BrowserSync when rapidly iterating, especially because it lets me have the same content loaded across multiple devices, including the desktop. When I make changes, the content can automatically be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use BrowserSync, however, you need to enable certain CSP rules. These should only be enabled during development, unless you’re using another framework or plugin that requires them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;ws://*&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;default-src&lt;/code&gt; directive — BrowserSync communicates over web sockets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;&#39;unsafe-inline&#39;&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;script-src&lt;/code&gt; directive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use &lt;code&gt;phonegap serve&lt;/code&gt; and the PhoneGap Developer app for a similar experience. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve only had limited luck in getting this to work well within my typical build setup (which has all sorts of stuff going on!), while BrowserSync works a peach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Kerri</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 21:57:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with technology for most of my life, starting at an early age on a Commodore 64. I still fondly remember the beige computer with slow floppy disk drive and learning BASIC from the manual. I love to develop apps (mobile and desktop)], and to help others do the same. I am an avid photographer, and can be found out and about making pictures of just about anything. I&amp;rsquo;m also an IT Consultant, working with websites and databases. I&amp;rsquo;ve written several books about mobile app development, and I&amp;rsquo;m active on various social networks &amp;mdash; some more than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I love to work with my fresh-water aquariums. I have two: a 37 gallon aquarium and a 20
gallon aquarium. Favorite fish include Bettas, Platys, Pictus, Plecos, and Catfish. I also enjoy
performing and composing music. My favorite instrument is the piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to inquire about consulting work, or anything in general, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kerrishotts.github.io/contact/&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Technical Book, part 1</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2014/06/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2014/06/08/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is part 1 of a series regarding technical writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not know, I&amp;rsquo;ve now written two pretty large technical books (one was the second edition of the first).
This post is more about the &lt;em&gt;process&lt;/em&gt; of
writing technical books, and later posts will go into more detail about my experiences with Packt Publishing (the
publisher).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-won-t-get-rich-writing-technical-books:a453c7a7ff454e847951e840794044f3&#34;&gt;You Won&amp;rsquo;t Get Rich Writing Technical Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, let&amp;rsquo;s make something very clear: technical books are mostly &lt;em&gt;niche&lt;/em&gt; products. They &lt;em&gt;aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; going to make you rich, and only a very few writers are going to either have enough name recognition or will have written enough books in order to generate significant income. This is a fact, and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t approach writing a technical book with &amp;ldquo;getting rich&amp;rdquo; in mind. It probably won&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons for this fact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical books often apply to a very narrow audience (by their very nature)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical books are commodities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical books are instantly obsolete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advances, royalties, and e-books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-books-apply-to-a-very-narrow-audience:a453c7a7ff454e847951e840794044f3&#34;&gt;Technical Books Apply to a Very Narrow Audience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be pretty obvious that the very nature of a technical book inherently limits the number of people who will purchase it. It&amp;rsquo;s not like the book you are writing is a fiction book that&amp;rsquo;s going to be the next &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; and will sell millions and millions of copies. Even if your book is about a widely used programming language or other well known topic, the number of people who are going to &lt;em&gt;buy&lt;/em&gt; your book are far less than those who are going to buy typical fiction (or even non-fiction) books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-books-are-commodities:a453c7a7ff454e847951e840794044f3&#34;&gt;Technical books are Commodities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is to say that the publisher has no incentive to spend a huge sum of money on a technical book, nor do they have an incentive to take their time with more than a couple editing passes and such. Most of this is due to the next point, but I think you should already understand why this is generally true: technology often moves far too quickly for typical publishing. Technology is &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;, writing and publishing is &lt;em&gt;slow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that the publisher doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to put a good book on the shelves &amp;ndash; of course they do. But neither do they have any incentive to pay you a large advance for it, nor do they have any incentive to allow you to take three or four years to &amp;ldquo;make it perfect&amp;rdquo; (much to the chagrin of perfectionists everywhere). In the first case, there&amp;rsquo;s always someone else willing to do the writing &amp;ldquo;just for fun&amp;rdquo; (and that isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be derogatory &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; like writing &lt;em&gt;just for fun&lt;/em&gt;), and there&amp;rsquo;s always the chance that the technology will quickly move on, leaving you in a perpetual state of editing and playing catch-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-books-are-instantly-obsolete:a453c7a7ff454e847951e840794044f3&#34;&gt;Technical Books are Instantly Obsolete&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to underscore the point, my book was about PhoneGap / Cordova 3.x. By the time the book was done, Cordova was at 3.4, and all the examples had been tested on that version. Two days after publication, Cordova 3.5 was released. Now, as far as I can tell, it broke nothing &amp;ndash; but there were occasions during the writing process where changes were released that &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; break things. And of course, there&amp;rsquo;s still the chance that Cordova 3.6 or a plugins release will &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; break the book. And, of course, being in print, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to fix it, short of submitting &lt;em&gt;errata&lt;/em&gt; and hoping that readers will look at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;advances-royalties-and-e-books:a453c7a7ff454e847951e840794044f3&#34;&gt;Advances, Royalties, and E-books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Packt generally offers a pretty good advance for their technical publishing, especially for first editions. (Later editions get lower advances, because it is assumed one won&amp;rsquo;t have to rewrite the whole thing. Which was not the case for the second edition of my book, but oh well!) Packt&amp;rsquo;s royalty rate is pretty good too, but it comes out to a few dollars per unit. Furthermore, you won&amp;rsquo;t see any royalty payments until your advance is paid off, so if a book sells slowly or poorly, it may be quite some time before you see any more income from your efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that I&amp;rsquo;m complaining in all of this, &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not&lt;/em&gt;. I love writing, and do it &lt;em&gt;for fun&lt;/em&gt;, so I have no problem with the economies involved here. But if I were to be honest, and I were to &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; the book based on the time it took and the amount I would charge a client, the book would easily have cost between $50,000 and $100,000 (USD). I won&amp;rsquo;t go into what my advance was, or what I expect my royalties to be, but let&amp;rsquo;s be blunt: it won&amp;rsquo;t pay for itself, or even come close. &lt;em&gt;And I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/em&gt; But if you were going into this &lt;em&gt;caring about breaking even or making goodly amounts of money&lt;/em&gt;, you are going to be in a world of hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, e-books and retailers add another wrinkle in this. The suggested price for my book is in the $50 range, while the price on Amazon is $33. The e-book price is even lower: $20. Obviously the royalties generated from these purchases are going to be lower. If the rest of the world is anything like me, I buy nearly all my books as e-books, and I suspect most people buying my book would do so as well. Again, &lt;em&gt;not complaining&lt;/em&gt;, but pointing out the economies involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-technical-books:a453c7a7ff454e847951e840794044f3&#34;&gt;Writing Technical Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of writing a technical book is&amp;hellip; intense. Most publishers will indicate that you can do write a technical book alongside of your full-time job, with only a few additional hours dedicated to the book. O, if that were true. &lt;em&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt;. (Maybe someone can, but not me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; is that you&amp;rsquo;ll be working at least an additional &lt;em&gt;part-time&lt;/em&gt; job (around 20 hours per week). Now, I&amp;rsquo;m sure this varies based on the type of book being written, but here&amp;rsquo;s how my process typically went:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the sample application for the chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug the sample application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test the sample application on various devices, and fix any issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the first pass of the text, applying special styles as necessary to mark certain parts as keywords, code, URLs, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the necessary graphics for the chapter (diagrams, screenshots, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy in the code samples from the application for the book, adjust formatting, add useful comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the text to ensure that everything makes sense, is in the right order, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Package the text and code and send it to the publisher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the process for the first few chapters, but after a while, one hears back from the publisher (and other technical reviewers &amp;ndash; life-savers, them!) with comments about the earlier chapters: about what didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense or didn&amp;rsquo;t work, etc. These comments are &lt;em&gt;invaluable&lt;/em&gt;, and the book wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be half as good without them. But now the process becomes all of the above (for the current chapter), and then add the  following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review comments from publisher / reviewer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise text accordingly (using best judgement &amp;ndash; there isn&amp;rsquo;t always room to respond to every comment).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise the code and graphics if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the code and text for the chapter to reflect any breaking changes (and test, again!), especially if the underlying platform has changed since the original writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repackage code, graphics, and text, and send to the publisher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, all of this goes on &lt;em&gt;while you are doing your regular job&lt;/em&gt;. Although I&amp;rsquo;m a consultant that gets to work remotely and gets to manage her time much more flexibly than others, even I found it difficult to manage both my &amp;ldquo;day job&amp;rdquo; and my &amp;ldquo;book job&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I could have done it working a 40-60 hour/week job alongside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, there were many coding and writing marathons going on each week: quite often the weekend would receive the brunt of this &amp;ndash; with 10-12 hour days for two or three days in a row to meet the deadline. Of course &lt;em&gt;during the week&lt;/em&gt; there were often long evenings as well &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to write a sample app in a week or two for a book, especially when it usually takes much, much longer to push an app to an app store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, no one is &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;, and so there were inevitably going to be errors in the book that neither me, nor the publisher, nor the reviewers were going to catch. This is a fact of writing books: &lt;em&gt;we&amp;rsquo;re all human&lt;/em&gt;. Some of these errors were my mistake &amp;ndash; others were issues caused by trying to keep up with the evolving technology stack I was writing about. In the case of this book, it is &lt;em&gt;absolutely true&lt;/em&gt; when I tell you that I was submitting changes to the text &lt;em&gt;a couple days before it was to be uploaded to the printers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s enough for part 1 of this series, I think. In the next section, I want to cover some of the tools I used in writing the book, and then I will go on to get into details regarding working with Packt Publishing and address areas where the process could use improvement, but also address the overall good experience of publishing with Packt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, keep writing/coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonegap 3.x Mobile Application Development Hotshot Released</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2014/06/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2014/06/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so proud to announce that my new book, &lt;em&gt;PhoneGap 3.x Mobile Application Development Hotshot&lt;/em&gt; is now available for
purchase. It&amp;rsquo;s an update to my earlier book, and it has been modernized and updated for Cordova 3.x. Although the title
includes &amp;ldquo;PhoneGap&amp;rdquo; in the name, it generally uses the Cordova Command Line Interface (&amp;ldquo;PhoneGap&amp;rdquo; is more recognizable
in the market).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book will guide you through the installation of the Cordova and PhoneGap CLIs and will also guide you through the
development of three fully functional and interesting mobile apps. These apps are cross-platform (they work on iOS 6+
and Android 4.x) and support multiple form factors (phone and tablet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first app is the most complex and is the one we spend seven chapters with. What starts out as a simple note-taking
app is grown over the course of several chapters into a app that can play and record audio, take photos, and record
video. When we&amp;rsquo;re done, it can also share content to social networks, and it can also adapt to different screen sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second app focuses on Google Maps and GPS &amp;ndash; it allows the user to record their location over a period of time. This
path then shows up on the map using Google&amp;rsquo;s polylines. There&amp;rsquo;s also an online chapter where we extend the app to use
native controls (for iOS 7 only).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final app proves that we can learn &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; have fun doing it, too. The app is a simple arcade-style game that uses the
HTML5 Canvas and the accelerometer. The second version of the app adds support for a high score table (stored using Parse,
a backend-as-a-service).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book we also focus on technologies related to mobile application development. We introduce &lt;strong&gt;RequireJS&lt;/strong&gt;, which
makes building large, complex apps easier with dependency management. We utilize &lt;strong&gt;Hammer.js&lt;/strong&gt; to provide gesture recognition
(for &lt;strong&gt;swipe-to-delete&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;fast touch recognition&lt;/strong&gt;). We also utilize &lt;strong&gt;CSS3 transitions and transforms&lt;/strong&gt; for smooth animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One possibly controversial decision is the use of the YASMF-Next framework in the book. First, I wanted to write a book
&lt;em&gt;about PhoneGap&lt;/em&gt;, not a book &lt;em&gt;about a specific framework&lt;/em&gt; like jQuery or Sencha Touch. Unfortunately, although it&amp;rsquo;s possible
to write apps without any framework, one quickly builds up a repository of reusable components that, over time, morph into
a framework themselves. And that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;YASMF-Next&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; a framework I&amp;rsquo;ve designed
that meets most of my needs when it comes to creating apps in PhoneGap. It&amp;rsquo;s young and immature, but it is being worked
on heavily. An earlier version of this framework was used in the prior edition of the book, but my coding has grown in the
last several months, and the new version of the framework reflects this. Furthermore, the framework is small &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s not
terribly complicated, which means that it can be used as a learning tool as well (much as Minix can be used as a learning
tool for operating system design). In addition, the book usually explains how YASMF-Next is accomplishing everything and
shows similar code for accomplishing the tasks if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to use the framework. And, of course, you can always take
the skills learned in the book and apply them to many of the other popular frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I wanted to thank all the reviewers who participated in making sure the content going into the book was accurate
(and that it made sense), and Steve Husting in particular who was roped into testing the code (Thanks &amp;ndash; you&amp;rsquo;re a trooper!).
I also wanted to thank all the hard workers at Packt Publishing who put everything together, kept me on task, limited my
ramblings (sometimes to no avail, sorry!), and got this out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? Use those &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; buttons at the top of this post, or visit the following links to purchase the
book! And if you&amp;rsquo;d be so kind to leave a review, that would be &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy the book:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/PhoneGap-Mobile-Application-Development-Hotshot-ebook/dp/B00KLAJ5Z0/&#34;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/phonegap-3-x-mobile-application-development-hotshot/book&#34;&gt;Packt Publishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the File API without callbacks</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2013/10/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2013/10/26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a given that working with the HTML5 API is a painful experience due to all those levels of callbacks. Even
a simple operation turns into something unnecessarily complex, and so I present FileManager &amp;ndash; a simple wrapper around frequently
used portions of the File API that uses Promises (or Q.js, specifically).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super easy to use, and while it&amp;rsquo;s officially part of the YASMF framework (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/photokandyStudios/YASMF-Next&#34;&gt;https://github.com/photokandyStudios/YASMF-Next&lt;/a&gt;), it doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on it outright (you can use the gist instead: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/kerrishotts/7147214&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/kerrishotts/7147214&lt;/a&gt;). It does require that Q.js be loaded prior to using it &amp;ndash; however you like doing that is up to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like to use Q.js/Promises, and use the File API a lot, you might just want to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/photokandyStudios/YASMF-Next/wiki/FileManager&#34;&gt;https://github.com/photokandyStudios/YASMF-Next/wiki/FileManager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/photokandyStudios/YASMF-Next/blob/master/lib/yasmf/util/fileManager.js&#34;&gt;https://github.com/photokandyStudios/YASMF-Next/blob/master/lib/yasmf/util/fileManager.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gist (stand-alone): &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/kerrishotts/7147214&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/kerrishotts/7147214&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a quick example, here&amp;rsquo;s how it makes life a lot easier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; fm &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; _y.FileManager(); &lt;span style=&#34;color: #888888&#34;&gt;// using YASMF&lt;/span&gt;
    fm.init ( fm.PERSISTENT, &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000DD; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;1024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #333333&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000DD; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;1024&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #888888&#34;&gt;// request the persistent file system with 1mb of space&lt;/span&gt;
         .then ( &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; () { &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; fm.readDirectoryContents ( &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;, {} ); } ) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #888888&#34;&gt;// read the current directory&lt;/span&gt;
         .then ( &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; ( entries ) { &lt;span style=&#34;color: #888888&#34;&gt;//process the entries } ) // do something with the entries&lt;/span&gt;
         .&lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;catch&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008800; font-weight: bold&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; ( anError ) { console.log (anError.code); } ) &lt;span style=&#34;color: #888888&#34;&gt;// log the error code&lt;/span&gt;
         .done ();
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to use it in your projects, it works in the Google Chrome (v30 or higher) and PhoneGap / Cordova (dependent upon platform support).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhoneGap, SELECTs, and 3D transforms, oh my!</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/quicktip/2012/11/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/quicktip/2012/11/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an app for a client, I was having an odd problem: the SELECT box wasn&amp;rsquo;t tappable on Android 2.x. It worked great on iOS. It worked great on Android 4.x. But on 2.x, it just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t respond to input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of frustrated debugging, I found this page after a Google search: &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4523309/select-box-not-displaying-on-android-in-phonegap&#34;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4523309/select-box-not-displaying-on-android-in-phonegap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what &amp;ndash; problem solved. I removed the code I was using that added a -webkit-transform:translate3d(0,0,0) on the parent element, and the SELECT box worked beautifully again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought you might want to know &amp;ndash; in case you ever had the same problem!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SOAP in a PhoneGap App</title>
      <link>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2012/09/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kerrishotts.github.io/post/2012/09/25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, yeah, so using SOAP is generally not the preferred solution when working from Javascript. It&amp;rsquo;s so much easier to handle data in JSON rather than in XML. But sometimes you can&amp;rsquo;t avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help, I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;em&gt;started&lt;/em&gt; a simple library that helps make our lives a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; bit easier. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing big yet, doesn&amp;rsquo;t validate the data yet, and surely has lots of bugs. In other words: &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t use it for production&lt;/em&gt; without understanding the potential glitches. If the data you are sending to the server is likely to have &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo;, be careful – the library will very likely barf. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s things I haven&amp;rsquo;t even started to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even so, it&amp;rsquo;s a start, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any additional libraries. I can verify that it works from within PhoneGap (which was the main point), at least on WebKit browsers. Android 2.x &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; have a bug with the &amp;ldquo;content-length&amp;rdquo; header – in which case, just remove that line. I have no idea about WP7 or WP8. On iOS, it just works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gist is here, under an MIT license: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3786070&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/3786070&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to fork, improve, use, etc. If you do find a bug or implement a fix, it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to share it back, but since it&amp;rsquo;s under MIT, you&amp;rsquo;re under no requirement to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>